Blake French

4704 Lake Forest Ave • San Diego, CA 92117 • 208-380-0086 • <u>blakefren@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/blakefren.ch</u> • <u>blakefren.ch</u>

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 7 years of experience in critical data-centric roles, including large-scale online advertising and semiconductor manufacturing. Background in designing and maintaining large-scale production systems, involving billions of records each. Experienced in multiple languages such as Python and C++. Currently pursuing a part-time masters in machine learning, and expect to graduate in the spring of 2023.

EXPERIENCE

Google San Diego, CA April 2020 – Present

Software Engineer

- Create and maintain systems to classify advertisements into an age-appropriate ratings scheme (AAA),
 which protects children from exposure to ads inappropriate for their age.
- Analyze and improve the performance of machine learning models for rating assets.
- Primary engineer on shopping AAA deployment, including design, analysis, pipelining, etc. for billions of Google shopping ad assets.
- Primary engineer on team infrastructure scheduling improvements; realized 50%+ alert reduction.
- Participate in regular code reviews and testing, team on-call duties, and interviewing and mentoring new engineers.

Micron Technology, Inc.

San Diego, CA / Boise, ID

August 2015 – April 2020

Senior Control Systems Engineer

- Created systems to automate analysis of and reactions to manufacturing process faults and anomalies, with the goal of reducing scrap, product variance, and RMAs.
- Realized multi-million dollar savings across product lines at multiple sites with these systems.
- Served as global SME for new tool/sensor integrations and non-standard control systems solutions.
- Enhanced system functionality with plugins and feature additions.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Graduate May 2023 [expected]

• Master of Science in Computer Science – Machine Learning Specification

Idaho State University

Graduate May 2015

- Bachelor of Science in Physics
- Bachelor of Science in Music

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python, SQL, C++, .NET/C# (in relative order of experience)
- Machine learning, mapreduce
- Python libraries: Torch, Tensorflow + Keras, pandas, sklearn
- Statistical process control techniques

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Armada Corps, Inc. Boise, ID December 2016 – September 2019

Board Member

- Make high-level decisions for the organization with the rest of the executive team.
- Developed website, wrote non-profit incorporation documents, and created other public-facing documents.